<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-24T17:33:28+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OCR-D</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry xml:lang="de"><title type="html">OCR-D bei der DHd in Paderborn</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2020/02/19/dhd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR-D bei der DHd in Paderborn" /><published>2020-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2020/02/19/dhd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2020/02/19/dhd.html">&lt;p&gt;Die OCR-D-Förderinitiative ist mit mehreren Vorträgen auf der DHd 2020 vertreten, die vom 2.-6. März in Paderborn stattfindet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In V15, am 5. März, stellt das OCR-D-Koordinierungsprojekt anhand von vier Thesen zur Volltexttransformation Ergebnisse und Perspektiven der Förderinitiative zur Diskussion. In der gleichen Sektion berichten die Kollegen des Modulprojekts zur Entwicklung eines Modellrepositoriums und einer Automatischen Schriftarterkennung für OCR-D über ihre Erkenntnisse zur Verwendung von Fraktur in deutschsprachigen Büchern. Weitere Informationen zu den Vorträgen finden Sie im &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conftool.com/dhd2020/index.php?page=browseSessions&amp;amp;form_session=124&amp;amp;presentations=show&quot;&gt;Programm der DHd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="paper" /><category term="DHd" /><summary type="html">Die OCR-D-Förderinitiative ist mit mehreren Vorträgen auf der DHd 2020 vertreten, die vom 2.-6. März in Paderborn stattfindet. In V15, am 5. März, stellt das OCR-D-Koordinierungsprojekt anhand von vier Thesen zur Volltexttransformation Ergebnisse und Perspektiven der Förderinitiative zur Diskussion. In der gleichen Sektion berichten die Kollegen des Modulprojekts zur Entwicklung eines Modellrepositoriums und einer Automatischen Schriftarterkennung für OCR-D über ihre Erkenntnisse zur Verwendung von Fraktur in deutschsprachigen Büchern. Weitere Informationen zu den Vorträgen finden Sie im Programm der DHd.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">OCR-D at the DHd in Paderborn</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2020/02/19/dhd.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR-D at the DHd in Paderborn" /><published>2020-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2020/02/19/dhd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2020/02/19/dhd.html">&lt;p&gt;The OCR-D funding initiative will be represented with several presentations at the DHd 2020, which will take place in Paderborn from 2-6 March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In V15, on March 5, the OCR-D coordination project will discuss the results and perspectives of the funding initiative on the basis of four theses on full text transformation. In the same section, the colleagues of the module project for the development of a model repository and automatic font recognition for OCR-D will report on their findings on the use of fracture in German-language books. For further information on the presentations see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.conftool.com/dhd2020/index.php?page=browseSessions&amp;amp;form_session=124&amp;amp;presentations=show&quot;&gt;the DHd programm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="paper" /><category term="DHd" /><summary type="html">The OCR-D funding initiative will be represented with several presentations at the DHd 2020, which will take place in Paderborn from 2-6 March. In V15, on March 5, the OCR-D coordination project will discuss the results and perspectives of the funding initiative on the basis of four theses on full text transformation. In the same section, the colleagues of the module project for the development of a model repository and automatic font recognition for OCR-D will report on their findings on the use of fracture in German-language books. For further information on the presentations see the DHd programm.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="de"><title type="html">Volltexte – die Zukunft alter Drucke: OCR-D-Workshop in Bonn</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2020/02/03/volltexte-die-zukunft-alter-drucke.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volltexte – die Zukunft alter Drucke: OCR-D-Workshop in Bonn" /><published>2020-02-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2020/02/03/volltexte-die-zukunft-alter-drucke</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2020/02/03/volltexte-die-zukunft-alter-drucke.html">&lt;p&gt;Am 12. Februar findet in Bonn der OCR-D-Workshop “Volltexte – die Zukunft alter
Drucke” statt. Die Erkenntnisse und Desiderate des DFG-Projekts werden dort
einem bereiten Publikum aus Entwicklern, OCR-Experten, Anwendern und
Fördergebern vorgestellt und diskutiert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Die ersten Vorträge am Vormittag stellen die OCR-D-Software selbst in den
Mittelpunkt. Diese wird mit ihrem Funktionsumfang und ihren technischen
Möglichkeiten vorgeführt sowie Spezifikationen und Dokumentationen als Basis
für deren Erstellung und Verwendung beschrieben. Die Erfahrungen und
Erkenntnisse, die die Software- Entwickler zur Praxis der OCR-Erstellung in
bestandshaltenden Einrichtungen gewonnen haben, sind mit Blick auf künftige
OCR-Projekte von übergeordnetem Interesse. Beschlossen wird der Vormittagsteil
in einer Podiumsdiskussion mit den Entwicklern aus den einzelnen
OCR-D-Modulprojekten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Die Nachmittagssektion ist der Diskussion über die Zukunft der OCR-D-Software
vorbehalten. Mit den Workshop-Teilnehmern sollen verschiedene Wege und
Möglichkeiten zur Implementierung der Software an bestandshaltenden
Einrichtungen und deren Überführung in den Praxiseinsatz erörtert werden. Daran
anschließend werden mögliche weitere Fördermaßnahmen des DFG-Projekts
besprochen, mit deren Hilfe die letzten Schritte zur letztlich anvisierten
massenhaften Prozessierung der VD-Titel gegangen werden können.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="workshop" /><summary type="html">Am 12. Februar findet in Bonn der OCR-D-Workshop “Volltexte – die Zukunft alter Drucke” statt. Die Erkenntnisse und Desiderate des DFG-Projekts werden dort einem bereiten Publikum aus Entwicklern, OCR-Experten, Anwendern und Fördergebern vorgestellt und diskutiert.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Full texts - the future of old prints: OCR-D-Workshop in Bonn</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2020/02/03/volltexte-die-zukunft-alter-drucke.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Full texts - the future of old prints: OCR-D-Workshop in Bonn" /><published>2020-02-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-02-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2020/02/03/volltexte-die-zukunft-alter-drucke</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2020/02/03/volltexte-die-zukunft-alter-drucke.html">&lt;p&gt;The OCR-D workshop “Full texts - the future of old prints” will take place in
Bonn on 12 February. The findings and desiderata of the DFG project will be
presented and discussed there with a broad audience of developers, OCR experts,
users and funding agencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first morning lectures will focus on the OCR-D software itself. It will be
demonstrated with its range of functions and technical possibilities,
specifications and documentation will be described as a basis for its creation
and use. The experiences and insights that the software developers have gained
on the creation of OCR in libraries are of special interest with regard to
future OCR projects. The morning section will be concluded in a panel
discussion with the developers of the OCR-D module projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon section is reserved for the discussion about the future of the
OCR-D software. The workshop participants will discuss various ways and
possibilities for implementing the software at libraries and transferring it to
practical use. Subsequently, possible further funding measures of the DFG
project will be discussed, with the help of which the last steps can be taken
towards the mass processing of the VD titles, which is ultimately targeted.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="workshop" /><summary type="html">The OCR-D workshop “Full texts - the future of old prints” will take place in Bonn on 12 February. The findings and desiderata of the DFG project will be presented and discussed there with a broad audience of developers, OCR experts, users and funding agencies.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="de"><title type="html">Kooperation mit Kitodo vereinbart</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/11/20/kooperation-mit-kitodo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kooperation mit Kitodo vereinbart" /><published>2019-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/11/20/kooperation-mit-kitodo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/11/20/kooperation-mit-kitodo.html">&lt;p&gt;Kitodo und OCR-D haben einen Letter of Intent zur Zusammenarbeit bei der
koordinierten und nachhaltigen Entwicklung und Bereitstellung von
OCR-Softwarelösungen zur Massenvolltextdigitalisierung unterzeichnet. Kitodo
ist eine quelloffene Softwaresuite für die Digitalisierung von Kulturgut in
bestandshaltenden Einrichtungen und im Bibliotheksbereich weit verbreitet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grundlegendes Ziel der Kooperation ist es, inhaltliche und konzeptionelle
Überschneidungen zwischen Kitodo und OCR-D zum Erzielen von Synergien in
technischer und organisatorischer Hinsicht zu nutzen. Es wird perspektivisch
angestrebt, OCR-D als eigenen Funktionsbereich in Kitodo.Production
aufzunehmen. OCR-D beabsichtigt in den kommenden Jahren, die entstandene
Softwarelösung zu einer stabil lauffähigen, breit eingesetzten sowie
ausführlich dokumentierten Softwarelösung auszubauen. Im gegenseitigen
Einverständnis und vor dem Hintergrund der anstehenden Implementierungsphase
von OCR-D tauschen sich die Kooperationspartner dazu vor allem über
Schnittstellen zu Kitodo.Production und aktuelle sowie kommende Entwicklungen
der OCR-Massenvolltextdigitalisierung aus. Mit Blick auf die technische
Integration von OCR-D in Kitodo.Production, wird Kitodo e.V. die
koordinierenden Einrichtungen des OCR-D-Projektes und die
Implementierungspartner mit seinen Erfahrungen umfassend unterstützen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="kitodo" /><category term="kooperation" /><summary type="html">Kitodo und OCR-D haben einen Letter of Intent zur Zusammenarbeit bei der koordinierten und nachhaltigen Entwicklung und Bereitstellung von OCR-Softwarelösungen zur Massenvolltextdigitalisierung unterzeichnet. Kitodo ist eine quelloffene Softwaresuite für die Digitalisierung von Kulturgut in bestandshaltenden Einrichtungen und im Bibliotheksbereich weit verbreitet.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">Cooperation with Kitodo signed</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/11/20/kooperation-mit-kitodo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cooperation with Kitodo signed" /><published>2019-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-11-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/11/20/kooperation-mit-kitodo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/11/20/kooperation-mit-kitodo.html">&lt;p&gt;Kitodo and OCR-D have signed a Letter of Intent to cooperate on the coordinated and sustainable development and provision of OCR software solutions for mass full text digitization. Kitodo is an open source software suite for the digitisation of cultural property and widely used in the library sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic aim of the cooperation is to make use of overlaps between Kitodo and OCR-D to achieve synergies in technical and organizational aspects. It will be perspectively aspired, to integrate OCR-D as a separate functional area in Kitodo.Production.. In the coming years, OCR-D intends to develop the resulting software solution to a stable executable, widely used and extensively documented software solution. In mutual agreement and in view of the upcoming implementation phase of OCR-D, the cooperation partners will exchange information on interfaces to Kitodo.Production and current and upcoming developments. In the coming years, OCR-D intends to develop the resulting software solution to a stable executable, widely used and extensively documented software solution. In mutual agreement and in view of the upcoming implementation phase of OCR-D, the cooperation partners will exchange information on Interfaces to Kitodo.Production and current and upcoming developments of the OCR mass full text digitization. With regard to the technical integration of OCR-D in Kitodo.Production, Kitodo e.V. willcoordinating institutions of the OCR-D project and the In the coming years, OCR-D intends to expand the resulting software solution into a stable, widely used and extensively documented software solution. In mutual agreement and against the background of the upcoming implementation phase of OCR-D, the cooperation partners will exchange information on interfaces to Kitodo.Production and current and future developments of the OCR mass full text digitization. With regard to the technical integration of OCR-D in Kitodo.Production, Kitodo e.V. will support the coordination project and the implementation partners with its extensive experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="kitodo" /><category term="kooperation" /><summary type="html">Kitodo and OCR-D have signed a Letter of Intent to cooperate on the coordinated and sustainable development and provision of OCR software solutions for mass full text digitization. Kitodo is an open source software suite for the digitisation of cultural property and widely used in the library sector.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="de"><title type="html">OCR-D bei der ICDAR 2019 in Sydney</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/08/23/icdar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR-D bei der ICDAR 2019 in Sydney" /><published>2019-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/08/23/icdar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/08/23/icdar.html">&lt;p&gt;Das OCR-D Paper „okralact – a multi-engine Open Source OCR training system“
(Konstantin Baierer, Rui Dong, Clemens Neudecker) wurde für den 5th
International Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing HIP 2019
(https://www.primaresearch.org/hip2019/) im Rahmen der ICDAR Konferenz 2019 in
Sydney (https://icdar2019.org/) angenommen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Quellcode zum dort vorgestellten Prototypen für eine multi-Enginge OCR
Trainingsinfrastruktur ist unter https://github.com/Doreenruirui/okralact zu
finden. Mit „Dataset of Pages from Early Printed Books with Multiple Font
Groups” ist zudem das Modulprojekt zur Entwicklung eines Modellrepositoriums
und einer automatischen Schriftarterkennung für OCR-D mit einem paper von
Mathias Seuret, Saskia Limbach, Nikolaus Weichselbaumer, Andreas Maier and
Vincent Christlein auf dem gleichen Workshop vertreten.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="paper" /><category term="ICDAR" /><category term="2019" /><summary type="html">Das OCR-D Paper „okralact – a multi-engine Open Source OCR training system“ (Konstantin Baierer, Rui Dong, Clemens Neudecker) wurde für den 5th International Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing HIP 2019 (https://www.primaresearch.org/hip2019/) im Rahmen der ICDAR Konferenz 2019 in Sydney (https://icdar2019.org/) angenommen.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">OCR-D at the ICDAR 2019 in Sydney</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/08/23/icdar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR-D at the ICDAR 2019 in Sydney" /><published>2019-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/08/23/icdar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/08/23/icdar.html">&lt;p&gt;The OCR-D paper “okralact - a multi-engine Open Source OCR training system (Konstantin Baierer, Rui Dong, Clemens Neudecker) was accepted for the 5th International Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing HIP 2019 (https://www.primaresearch.org/hip2019/) in the context of the ICDAR Conference 2019 in Sydney (https://icdar2019.org/).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The source code for the prototype for a multi-engine OCR Training infrastructure presented there is available at https://github.com/Doreenruirui/okralact. Training infrastructure is available at https://github.com/Doreenruirui/okralact for find. With “Dataset of Pages from Early Printed Books with Multiple Font Groups” the module project for the development of a model repository and an automatic font recognition for OCR-D is also at the same workshop with a paper of Mathias Seuret, Saskia Limbach, Nikolaus Weichselbaumer, Andreas Maier and Vincent Christlein.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Elisabeth Engl</name></author><category term="paper" /><category term="ICDAR" /><category term="2019" /><summary type="html">The OCR-D paper “okralact - a multi-engine Open Source OCR training system (Konstantin Baierer, Rui Dong, Clemens Neudecker) was accepted for the 5th International Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing HIP 2019 (https://www.primaresearch.org/hip2019/) in the context of the ICDAR Conference 2019 in Sydney (https://icdar2019.org/).</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="de"><title type="html">OCR-D auf EuropeanaTech Insights</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/08/09/europeanatech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR-D auf EuropeanaTech Insights" /><published>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/08/09/europeanatech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/de/2019/08/09/europeanatech.html">&lt;p&gt;Das Online Journal „EuropeanaTech Insights“ widmete aus Anlass der DATeCH 2019 sein letztes Heft dem Thema Optical Character Recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neben Artikeln über OCR an bengalischen und arabischen Texten der British Library und über automatische Artikelerkennung in finnischen Zeitschriften werden das OCR-D Projekt und erste Ergebnisse daraus ausführlich unter dem Titel &lt;a href=&quot;https://pro.europeana.eu/page/issue-13-ocr#ocr-d-an-end-to-end-open-source-ocr-framework-for-historical-documents&quot;&gt;„OCR-D: An End-to-end open source OCR framework for historical documents“&lt;/a&gt; vorgestellt. Verfasser des Papers sind C. Neudecker, K. Baierer, M. Federbusch (Staatsbibliothek Berlin), K.M. Würzner, M. Boenig (Berlin-Brandenburgische Akademie der Wissenschaften), E. Herrmann (Herzog-August Bibliothek Wolfenbüttel), V. Hartmann (Karlsruher Institut für Technologie).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><category term="DATeCH" /><category term="2019" /><summary type="html">Das Online Journal „EuropeanaTech Insights“ widmete aus Anlass der DATeCH 2019 sein letztes Heft dem Thema Optical Character Recognition.</summary></entry><entry xml:lang="en"><title type="html">OCR-D auf EuropeanaTech Insights</title><link href="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/08/09/europeanatech.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OCR-D auf EuropeanaTech Insights" /><published>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/08/09/europeanatech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ocr-d.github.io/en/2019/08/09/europeanatech.html">&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of DATeCH 2019, the online journal “EuropeanaTech Insights” dedicated its last issue to the topic of optical character recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to articles on OCR in Bengali and Arabic texts from the British Library and on automatic article recognition in Finnish journals, the OCR-D project and its first results are presented in detail under the title &lt;a href=&quot;https://pro.europeana.eu/page/issue-13-ocr#ocr-d-an-end-to-end-open-source-ocr-framework-for-historical-documents&quot;&gt;“OCR-D: An End-to-end open source OCR framework for historical documents”&lt;/a&gt;. Authors of the paper are C. Neudecker, K. Baierer, M. Federbusch (Berlin State Library), K.M. Würzner, M. Boenig (Berlin-Brandenburg Academy of Sciences and Humanities), E. Herrmann (Duke-August Library Wolfenbüttel), V. Hartmann (Karlsruhe Institute of Technology).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="paper" /><category term="DATeCH" /><category term="2019" /><summary type="html">On the occasion of DATeCH 2019, the online journal “EuropeanaTech Insights” dedicated its last issue to the topic of optical character recognition.</summary></entry></feed>